tv3.ie 2016-11-16

# TV3 - Privacy Policy

This privacy statement is applicable to all TV3 online services.

TV3 respects the privacy of its online users and will protect that privacy as vigorously as possible. This privacy statement may be updated from time to time to reflect changes to legislation or technology.

TV3 Adheres to the Data Protection Acts 1988 & 2003 and Regulation 5 of Statutory Instrument 336 2011

TV3 does not collect information that personally identifies individuals except when individuals provide such specific information on a voluntary basis. There may be occasions where specific personal information is requested before an individual can enter certain sections of TV3's site or where registration helps us to ensure that content standards on these sections of the site are rigorously upheld or that contact can be made with prize winners or where a user requests to be sent push notifications. Information requested in order to personalise the Tv3.ie homepage or any other TV3 site section would be a similar example.

In all such cases, TV3 will collect only information that is voluntarily provided by the user and undertakes that such information will be kept strictly confidential. Individual information provided to TV3 to gain access to any TV3 site will not be sold or made available to a third party outside the TV3 group of companies.

TV3 does reserve the right, however, to perform statistical analyses of user behaviour and characteristics, in order to measure interest in, comments or feedback on, and use of the various sections of its sites or any content shown and type and manner in which such is watched and advertisements presented so as to improve design and navigation and to gather marketing information.

Users should be aware that certain both personal and non-personal information and data may be automatically collected by TV3 through the operation of what are called "cookies". "Cookies" are small text files that identify an individual computer's browser entering a web site. They allow the site to track that browser's movement through the site over several sessions. Through cookies, a web site can recognise repeat users, facilitate the user's access to and use of the site and allow a site to track usage behaviour that will allow content improvements. TV3 uses cookies only for the above-mentioned purposes and will not use them to identify users or to track non-TV3 usage.

If you do not want a cookie placed on your computer by TV3, you may disable cookies altogether by modifying the Preferences section of Google Chrome or Internet Explorer browser (under Edit/Preferences/Advanced). Note that it is possible that some aspects of TV3 sites may be unavailable to you if you choose this option.

Please be advised that cookies are necessary for Apps and if you choose to disable App cookies it may impede your mobile device access.

For further information please see our cookies policy and our privacy policy

TV3 takes your security responsibilities seriously, we employ the most appropriate physical and technical measures and review these measures regularly.

TV3 is not responsible for the privacy practices of any external online services which may be accessed through your use of TV3's online services please review their different privacy statements as they may be subject to different privacy laws.

If you wish to contact TV3 directly about the processing of personal data please write to us at TV3, Westgate Business Park, Ballymount, Dublin 24

If you would like to contact TV3 directly by telephone on 01 4193333 or by email: [online@tv3.ie](mailto:online@tv3.ie)

TV3 is committed to protecting you and your family's personal information when you are using TV3's online services. We want our services to be safe and enjoyable environments for our audience. This privacy policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us by phone, text, by email or in letters or through use of TV3 services online or players at home or via mobile devices.

In order to provide you with the full range of TV3 services, we sometimes need to collect information about you.

All information provided to us by you will be treated with the utmost confidentiality in accordance with all applicable legislative and regulatory standards such as the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003, (as amended). If you ever decide that you no longer wish us to keep or use information or you want the information to be revised or updated, please feel free to contact us. We will remove or amend the information as appropriate in accordance with applicable legislative and regulatory requirements.

By using our online services you are accepting the terms of this privacy policy.

#### The privacy policy explains the following:

What information TV3 may collect about you when you use our online services?

When you visit our online services our web server collects information about your visit for our statistical analysis such as: the number of people who visit the website or use the App, the date and time of visits, the number of pages that you have viewed, information on the selection of shows you watch.how much time you have spent using our online services and what are the most popular sections of our online services

#### How TV3 will use information we collect about you?

TV3 will use your personal information for a number of purposes including the following: to provide our service, activities or online content, to provide you with information about these services and to deal with your requests and enquiries;

TV3 may contact you for reasons related to the service, activity or online content you have signed up for, (e.g. to provide you with password reminders or to notify you that a particular service, activity or online content has been suspended for maintenance);

Where we are offering personalised services, we may need to analyse the information you supply so that we can offer you a better personalisation service or to contact you about a comment you have sent us.

In order to ensure that the most relevant type of advertising is presented to you while using the 3Player or our online services, information can be analysed to allow TV3 to show a selection of advertisements to different viewers. We may use information we collect from you while using our services to choose which adverts you see. We may engage with certain companies to ensure that any advertisements presented to you are more useful and relevant. Sometimes this is based on personal data that these companies provide to us. Our IT systems may analyze your viewing information to provide you with suitable advertising but at no point will we process any sensitive category information such as religion, race, sexual orientation or health.

If you do not wish to see adverts that are based on the information we hold about you, you can opt out in your account settings.

We use IP addresses and device identifiers to identify the location of users, to block disruptive use, to establish the number of visits from different countries and to determine whether you are accessing the services from the Ireland or not as sometimes content is bought for Irish viewers only and you may not be allowed to watch this content from other countries. We can also use your postal code or local address area to ensure that you are not shown advertisements that are irrelevant to you.

The information we collect allows us to put in place more relevant adverts so that viewers will see adverts that are relevant to them or related to products or services available to them due to their viewing location in Ireland.

We use analysis and research purposes so that we may monitor and improve the services, products and content offered by TV3 to provide you with the most user-friendly navigation experience. TV3 may also use and disclose information in for marketing and strategic development purposes to business partners but only under strict contractual and security controls.

#### When TV3 may use your details to contact you?

TV3 may contact you in relation to any service, activity or online content you have signed up for in order to ensure that TV3 can deliver the services to you;

TV3 may contact you in relation to any correspondence we receive from you or any comment or complaint you make about TV3's services.

You may be contacted in relation to the personalised services you are using or in relation to any contribution you have submitted to TV3.

TV3 may invite you to participate in surveys about TV3 services (participation is always voluntary); and for marketing purposes, where you have agreed to this.

#### Will TV3 disclose your details to anyone else?

We will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies.

Generally, we will only use your information within TV3 group of companies.

However, sometimes TV3 uses third parties to process your information on our behalf, for example to provide services or analysis. TV3 requires these third parties to comply strictly with its instructions and TV3 requires that they do not use your personal information for their own business purposes, unless you have explicitly consented to the use of your personal information in this way.

We may request that you sign-in via a third party service (e.g. Facebook) to participate in a game/use an app.

In such instances you will be presented with a dialog box which will ask for your permission to allow your personal information (e.g. your full name, date of birth, work/school history) to be provided to TV3.

Your personal data is held on secure servers hosted by our Internet Service Provider. The nature of the Internet is such that we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us via the Internet. No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. However, we will take all reasonable steps (including appropriate technical and organisational measures) to protect your personal data.

Any changes to this Website Privacy Statement will be posted online so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

Please note that any site that you may connect to from here is not covered by this Privacy Policy.

A "cookie" is a small text file that's stored on your computer, tablet or phone when you visit a website.

Cookies let you navigate between pages efficiently, storing your preferences and generally improving your experience of a website. If you do not use cookies the website will think you are a new user each time and may require you to use login details each time.

Some cookies are deleted when you close down your browser. These are known as session cookies. Others remain on your device until they expire or you delete them from your cache. These are known as persistent cookies and enable us to remember things about you as a returning visitor.

#### Why do we use cookies?

TV3 uses cookies to collect information about visitors' use of the website, including things like connection speed, operating system details, the time and duration visits and IP addresses.

The information collected by cookies enables TV3 to understand the use of its site, including the number of visitors it has, the pages viewed per session, time exposed to particular pages etc. This in turn helps to provide visitors with a better experience.

TV3 will not attempt to personally identify visitors from their IP addresses.

Generally speaking, cookies do not contain personal information from which you can be identified, unless you have furnished such information to the website.

Cookies do not in any way compromise the security of your computer. Visitors can use most of the features on this website with no loss of functionality if cookies are disabled from the web browser.

Cookies are essential for us to provide a product or service you have requested and to provide a secure online environment.

However, Apps require cookies to be enabled in order for the service to function properly.

Cookies can let us know if there are error messages from web pages.

What kind of cookies do we have?

Analytics - these cookies help us to understand how popular different pages on the site are so we can improve the site content and performance

Technical - these cookies are required for the technical functioning of the website

Site cookies - these cookies are used to provide functionality within the site to make it easier to use and to improve the user experience

3rd Party Social - where we have integrated social media sites into our TV3 online services, those partners sometimes set cookies

3rd Party Advertising - TV3's online services are funded entirely from advertising and our partner advertisers set cookies to help them in delivering ads to the site.

#### Ad-Blocking Detection

Our website uses JavaScript to detect the use of ad blocking extensions for web browsers. This script is implemented in the source code of our website. The script simulates the display of an ad and confirms that it is displayed on a user's device. To do this, we do not store any information on users' devices and process no personal data. If we detect that a user deploys an ad blocker, we may interact with them on the use of ad blockers and/or adapt the content available to them. We reserve the right to restrict access to our websites if users do not agree to the use of ad blocker detection mechanisms.

#### What about cookies on mobile devices and App?

Generally cookies are not used on mobile devices and instead other methods are used to help deliver the best service to users on devices.

TV3 use Client/Device Generated Identifier: A device identifier (ID) set and/or made available by the operating system. Examples include: Apple's Identifier for Advertisers (IDFA), Google's Android ID, Universal Device ID (UDID) and MAC Address.

Users may or may not be able to control or change a device-generated identifier.

To compile statistics off mobile devices TV3 use Statistical ID: Analgorithm for identifying a device. Typical device attributes include: the type of device a user has and the IP address

The most similar tracking to a cookie is used by TV3's use of HTML5 Cookie Tracking: This Involves storing a cookie-like file in HTML5 local storage on the device.

Universal Login Tracking: Requires consumers to log into different experiences using a pre-existing login rather than create a unique one for that experience. This type of tracking is limited to specific vendors, but enables companies with this type of universal login to gather data across applications and devices.

#### What do I do if I want to disable all cookies?

If you want to prevent websites from using cookies, please see below instructions for changing your web browser settings for the most popular web browsers. Please note our Apps and player require cookies to be enabled in order for the service to function properly.

If you disable cookies, you will not be able to use some of our online and mobile services.

If using Internet Explorer's browser: Go to the 'Tools' menu

Click on 'Internet Options'

Click the 'Security' tab

Highlight the 'Internet' zone (selected by default)

Select security level 'High' for this zone

Click on 'OK'

If you access the web using Google Chrome: Click the Chrome menu button, located to the right of the browser toolbar.

Select Settings.

Click Show advanced settings.

In the "Privacy" section, click the Content settings button.

In the "Cookies" section, click "Block Cookies by default"

If you use Mozilla Firefox: Open the Edit menu and choose Preferences.

Under the Privacy & Security category, choose Cookies. (If no subcategories are visible, double-click the category to expand the list.)

Click the following radio button: Disable cookies

Please note If you visit TV3 on social media sites, the cookies policy of that social media site will apply.

#### About use of Intercom Services:

We use third-party analytics services to help understand your usage of our services. In particular, we provide a limited amount of your information (such as your email address and sign-up date) to Intercom, Inc. ("Intercom") and utilize Intercom to collect data for analytics purposes when you visit our website or use our product. Intercom analyzes your use of our website and/or product and tracks our relationship so that we can improve our service to you. We may also use Intercom as a medium for communications, either through email, or through messages within our product(s). As part of our service agreements, Intercom collects publicly available contact and social information related to you, such as your email address, gender, company, job title, photos, website URLs, social network handles and physical addresses, to enhance your user experience. For more information on the privacy practices of Intercom, please visit http://docs.intercom.io/privacy. Intercom's services are governed by Intercom's terms of use which can be found at http://docs.intercom.io/terms. If you would like to opt out of having this information collected by or submitted to Intercom, please contact us
